

SHOVON BASAK

Fullstack Web Developer

About Me

Seasoned Full Stack Web Developer with 6+ years of diverse industry experience, from fast growing startups to multinational corporations. Dedicated to building scalable solutions that positively impact thousands if not millions globally. A fast learner and effective communicator, with a track record of successfully managing and mentoring other team members.

Professional Experience

Neumann Kaffee Gruppe - Hamburg, Germany Senior Software Developer (Remote) September 2021 - Present

- Designed and developed full features, encompassing Django Backend code, jQuery Front-end, and REST API, utilized by a mobile app.
- Implemented a reporting system using Vue.js to visualize data effectively.
- Led the development of a mapping feature, leveraging Vue.js and Google Map's javascript SDK, to track and map geographical locations.
- Worked on the development of a gallery app using Next.js to browse and display images from various storage services.
- Collaborated closely with the DevOps team to orchestrate the migration of our system from a single compute instance hosted environment to a Dockerized and Kubernetes-managed infrastructure.

Field Buzz - Dhaka, Bangladesh

Software Engineer

August 2020 - August 2021

Junior Software Engineer

May 2018 - August 2020

- · Led a small development team and communication with consultants.
- Developed and maintained features for projects using the SaaS model, handling high transaction volumes.
- Scripted data manipulation on the production server.
- Implemented RESTful APIs with versioning support.
- Worked on Authentication & Role based authorization feature.
- Created Python libraries applicable across various company projects.

iQuantile - Dhaka, Bangladesh Junior Software Developer January 2018 - May 2018

Proactively contributed project enhancement ideas in team meetings.Assisted colleagues with troubleshooting, debugging, and development.

- Assisted boiledgaes with a bubieshooting, debagging, and development
- Analyzed client requirements and implemented projects from scratch.
- Built RESTful APIs for frontend developers and integrated 3rd party libraries.

My Contact

- **(** +880-1989-525-618
- Dhaka, Bangladesh
- www.shovon.dev
- github.com/ShovonBasak
- (in) linkedin.com/in/ShovonBasak

Technical

- · Python, Javascript, Typescript
- · Django, React, Next.js
- Database (PostgreSQL, MongoDB)
- · Docker, AWS, CI/CD
- Others: Flask, Fast API, Vue.js, Express.js
- Additional: PySpark

Soft Skills

- Observation
- · Decision making
- Communication
- Multi-tasking

Education

American International University - Bangladesh B.Sc Software Engineering January 2015 - April 2018 CGPA: 3.80/4.0

Achievements

2018 - 2021

As a lead Software Engineer successfully implemented 6 production ready system using Django & Vue.js

2022 - 2024

Transformed a non-scalable single-server app into a scalable solution through containerization and streamlined deployment processes.